EDGAR ROMERO

Email: archhdedd@gmail.com Phone: +1 (916) 826-0385

Address: 7924 Pepitone Ct. Sacramento, CA, 95828

Background

My education and work experience have made me a specialist in the design of urban environments, with knowledge of architectural guidelines in urban development and sustainability for natural environments. I am proactive, responsible, and passionate about serving the community with a motivated attitude of learning and collaboration. Since 2012, starting in Mexico I developed in the area of Architecture under the construction company, as well as on my own projects such as: project budgets, topographical surveys, residential designs and project management. Since March 2017, in the United States I have worked as a carpenter for 8 years in both commercial and residential environments on projects that required full construction processes such as planning, surveying, permitting and executing the project as well as having the work inspected for correctness. I have learned important skills like: Teamwork, project management, and the residential codes here in the Sacramento and surrounding counties. I also worked at Costco company as a stocker in the produce department as well as other departments as needed. I currently work as a carpenter and specialize in remodeling.

Skills

- Autocad, Photosho, Artlantis, Sketchup, Global Mapper, Neodata, Revit, 3ds Max, Microsoft Office.
- Collaboration and working well with others. Leadership and problem solving.
- Bilingual; English and Spanish

Work Experience

•	Nix Construction Inc., Ibarra Construction (Carpenter Framer/Gral. Construction)	2023-24
•	Costco Wholesale (Stocker)	2023-23
•	Golden Key Construction Inc. (Carpenter Framer)	2021-23
•	Unique Design Homes Inc. (Carpenter Framer)	2019-20
•	Patriot, Timberworks Inc., Production Inc., Erickson Framing CA LLC, Advantage C	Construction
	Inc. (Carpenter Framer)	2017-19
•	CCR INGENIEROS S.A DE CV.	2016
	P = P + P + P + P + P + P + P + P + P +	

Construction Resident (Building). Construction Resident (Civil), Estimations, work log.

• ROCA S.A DE C.V (LA HUERTA, JAL.)

2012-15

Project budgets, topographical surveys, residential designs and project management and design.

• AM ARQUITEKTOS S.A DE C.V (MELAQUE, JAL.)

2010-2011

Sckeching and visited construction sites and wrote reports.

SOCIAL SERVICE IN URBAN DEVELOPMENT, La Huerta, Jalisco

2014

2010-15

Graphing Urban Development Plan, Graphing plans for the regularization of properties in the Municipality of La Huerta.

Education

Bachelor of Architecture. Specializing in Sustentable Urban Development Instituto Tecnológico Superior de la Huerta, La Huerta, Jal. México. Transcript of BA in Architecture by IEE (International Education Evaluation).

Complimentary Education

- vank anna vann / - vararena va	
Architecture Congress (Public Space, Sustainability in Construction, BIM, Architecture	May 2014
with Alternative Materials, Bioclimatic Architecture, Smart Installations, Landscape	
Architecture and Rehabilitation of Existing Buildings).	
Architecture Congress (Sustainable Buildings, Soil Mechanics, Trends in Architecture,	Oct 2014
Sustainable Urbanism, Topographic Surveys).	
Rendering Course ~ Arquitectos Fonseca	Jun 2015
NeoData (Unit Prices, Estimates)	